BU Records: Phi Delta Phi, Inclusive: 1946-1971, undated, Bulk: 1950-1958, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Phi Delta Phi
Inclusive: 1946-1971, undated, Bulk: 1950-1958, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/129
Phi Delta Phi
1 document box.
The Phi Delta Phi records include administrative records, correspondence, and literary productions related to the Hemphill Inn chapter at Baylor University.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Phi Delta Phi is an international legal society established in 1869 at the University of Michigan with the intent to foster a higher standard of professional ethics within the legal world. There are over 130 active chapters (known as “Inns”) across the world and over 200,000 initiated members.
The Hemphill Inn of Phi Delta Phi was established at Baylor on 1949 October 21 and became the 78th Inn of the international organization. Members of the Justinian Society of the Baylor Law School, previously known as the Pre-Law club, petitioned for and were granted a charter to become an Inn of Phi Delta Phi. The namesake “Hemphill” Inn came from John Hemphill, the first Chief Justice of the Texas Supreme Court.
Scope and Content
This collection begins in 1947 and ends in 1971, with some items undated. The Administrative Records series includes directories for law school members as well as members of the organization, financial information, initiation reports, and the original petition and resolution of the organization. The Correspondence series includes letters sent and letters received by the organization as well as event and membership invitations to pledges. The Literary Productions series includes clippings, bulletins, relevant publications the organization received, various histories, and materials related to Baylor courses, including syllabi and final exams.
Some materials in the collection were compiled over time by previous Texas Collection staff members and kept in subject files. These materials were added to the collection during processing.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, this collection was arranged by document type and in labeled folders. Most of the original folder titles were retained. Currently, the collection is arranged in three series: I. Administrative Records, II. Correspondence, and III. Literary Productions. Within the three series, folders are arranged alphabetically and items within folders are arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/129. Acquired 0-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
"About Phi Delta Phi International." Phi Delta Phi. Accessed 2017 December 20.
"International Locations." Phi Delta Phi. Accessed 2017 December 20.
"John Hemphill Inn Installed at Baylor University." The Brief 45, no. 2 (1949-1950 Winter): 90-168.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Societies, etc.; Baylor University -- Students.; Baylor University. Justinian Society -- Records and correspondence.; Phi Delta Phi. Hemphill Inn (Baylor University) -- Records and correspondence.
Subjects
Greek letter societies -- Texas -- Waco.; Law students -- Societies, etc.; Lawyers -- Societies, etc.; Professional associations -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Financial records.
- Administrative Records, 1949-1959, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains materials relating to the operation of Phi Delta Phi at Baylor. It includes financial statements, various reports, information about members and potential initiates in the Law School. This series is in average condition.
  - Annual Financial Statement, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exchequer’s Report on Initiations, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial Statements, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Inter Fraternity Agreement on Pledging Procedures, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Notes and Rosters, 1954-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Petition Submitted by the Justinian Society Legal Fraternity, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Resolution of Hemphill Inn of Phi Delta Phi, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1950-1958, undated; 2
  This series contains letters sent from and to the organization, as well as invitations to pledges for events and initiation into the organization. This series is in good condition
  - Letters Received, 1950-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters Sent, 1954-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Membership and Event Invitations, 1950-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Literary Productions, 1946-1971, undated; 3
  This series contains various publications produced or received by the organization, both locally and nationally. This includes bulletins, clippings, histories, and materials related to Law courses at Baylor. This series is in average condition.
  - Administrative Bulletins, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1946-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Course Materials, 1949-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History of the Hutcheson Colony/Phi Delta Phi at the University of Houston, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Publications Received, 1953-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Social Activities, 1949-1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)